export const quizData = [
    {
        question: "Which of the following are called Key Industrial animals?",
        options:["Producers","Tertiary consumers","Primary consumers","None of these"],
        answer: "Primary consumers"
    },
    {
        question: "Forming of Association in India is",
        options:["Legal Right","Illegal Right","Natural Right","Fundamental Right"],
        answer: "Fundamental Right"
    },
    {
        question: "The Samkhya School of Philosophy was founded by",
        options:["Gautam Buddha","Mahipala","Gopala","Kapila"],
        answer: "Kapila"
    },
    {
        question: "Pustaz grasslands are situated at?",
        options:["South Africa","China","Hungary","USA"],
        answer: "Hungary"
    },
    {
        question: "Chelaiya Samiti is related to which of the following?",
        options:["Banking sector","Insurance sector","Health Sector","Tax reforms"],
        answer: "Tax reforms"
    },
];

export const hindidata =[
    {
        question: "भारत का राष्ट्रीय ध्वज क्या है?",
        options:["ग्रैंड यूनियन फ्लैग","तिरंगा","इंद्रधनुष ध्वज","लाल-सोबुज"],
        answer: "तिरंगा" 
    },
    {
        question: "तिरंगे झंडे में कितने रंग होते हैं?",
        options:["3","4","5","2"],
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        question: "राष्ट्रीय ध्वज की लंबाई, चौड़ाई का अनुपात कितना होता है?",
        options:["2:3","4:2","1:3","3:2"],
        answer: "3:2"   
    },
    {
        question: "तिरंगे झंडे के चक्र में कितनी तिलिया होती है?",
        options:["28 तीलियां","25 तीलियां","23 तीलियां","24 तीलियां"],
        answer: "24 तीलियां" 
    },
    {
        question: "भारत के राष्ट्रीय पक्षी का नाम क्या है?",
        options:["तीतर","कबूतर","मोर","तोते"],
        answer: "मोर"    
    },
]